be a long journey end of Chapter 18
[Music]
you
this is a librivox recording all librivox recordings are in the public
domain for more information or to volunteer please visit librivox.org this recording by jay hall
The Wonderful Wizard of Oz by l frank Baum Chapter 19 Attacked by the Fighting Trees
The next morning Dorothy kissed the pretty green girl goodbye and they all
shook hands with the soldier with the green whiskers, who had walked with him
as far as the gate. When the Guardian of the Gate saw them again he wondered
greatly that they could leave the beautiful City to get into new trouble.
But he at once unlocked their spectacles, which he put back into the green box, and
gave them many good wishes to carry with them. “You are now our ruler,” he said to
the Scarecrow; “so you must come back to us as soon as possible.” “I certainly shall
if I am able,” the Scarecrow replied; “but I must help Dorothy get home, first.” As
Dorothy bade the good-natured Guardian alas farewell she said: “I have been very
kindly treated in your lovely City, and everyone has been good to me. I cannot
tell you how grateful I am.” “Don’t try, my dear,”
he answered. “We should like to keep you with us, but if it is your wish to return
to Kansas, I hope you will find a way.” He then opened the gate of the outer wall,
and they walked forth and started upon their journey. The sun shone brightly as
our friends turned their faces toward the Land of the South. They were all in
the best of spirits, and laughed and chatted together. Dorothy was once more
filled with the hope of getting home, and the Scarecrow and the Tin Woodman were
glad to be of use to her. As for the Lion,
he sniffed the fresh air with the light and whisk his tail from side to side and
pure joy at being in the country again, while Toto ran around them and chased
the moss and butterflies, barking merrily all the time. “City life does not agree
with me at all,” remarked the Lion, as they walked along at a brisk pace.
“I have lost much flesh since I lived there, and now I am anxious for a chance
to show the other beasts how courageous I have grown.” They now turned
and took a last look at the Emerald City.
All they could see was a mass of towers and steeples behind the green walls, and
high up above everything the spires in dome of the Palace of Oz. “Oz was not such
a bad Wizard, after all,” said the Tin Woodman, as he felt his heart rattling
around in his breast. “He knew how to give me brains, and very good brains, too,” said
the Scarecrow.
“If Oz had taken a dose of the same courage he gave me,” added the Lion, “he
would have been a brave man.” Dorothy said nothing.
Oz had not kept the promise he made her, but he had done his best, so she forgave
him. As he said, he was a good man, even if
he was a bad Wizard. The first day’s journey was through the green fields and
bright flowers that stretched about the Emerald City on every side. They slept
that night on the grass, with nothing but the stars over them; and they rested very
well indeed. In the morning they traveled on until they came to a thick wood. There
was no way of going around it, for it seemed to extend to the right and left
as far as they could see; and, besides, they did not dare change the direction
of their journey for fear of getting lost. So they looked for the place where
it would be easiest to get into the forest. The Scarecrow, who was in the lead,
finally discovered a big tree with such wide spreading branches that there was
room for the party to pass underneath. So he walked forward to the tree, but just
as he came under the first branches they bent down and twined around him, and the
next minute he was raised from the ground and flung headlong among his
fellow-travellers This did not hurt the Scarecrow, but it surprised him, and he
looked rather dizzy when Dorothy picked him up is there another space between
this trees,” called the Lion. “Let me try it first,” said the Scarecrow, “for it doesn’t
hurt me to get thrown about.” He walked up to another tree, as he spoke, but its
branches immediately seized him and tossed him back again. “This is strange,”
exclaimed Dorothy. “What shall we do?” “The trees seemed to have made up their
mind to fight us, and stop our journey,” remarked the Lion. “I believe I will try it myself,”
said the and shouldering his axe, he marched up to the first tree that had handled the
Scarecrow so roughly. When a big branch bent down to seize him the Woodman
chopped at it so fiercely that he cut it in two. At once the tree began shaking
all its branches as if in pain, and the Tin Woodman passed safely under it. “Come
on!” he shouted to the others. “Be quick!” They all ran forward and passed under
the tree without injury, except Toto, who was caught by a small branch and shaken
until he howled. But the Woodman promptly chopped off the branch and set the
little dog free. The other trees of the forest did nothing to keep them back, so
they made up their minds that only the first row of trees could bend down their
branches, and that probably these were the policemen of the forest, and given
this wonderful power in order to keep strangers out of it. The four travelers
walked along with ease through the trees until they came to the far edge of the
wood. Then, to their surprise, they found before them a high wall which seemed to
be made of white china. It was smooth, like the surface of a dish, and higher
than their heads. “What shall we do now?” asked Dorothy. “I will make a ladder,” said
the Tin Woodman, “for we certainly must